<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Morning Digest - Personalized News</title>
    <link>https://CarlosVitorino.github.io/morning-digest/</link>
    <description>Your personalized morning news digest with clickbait filtering. Topics: Technology, Science, Business, Politics, Software Development, Gadgets.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 18:15:16 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://CarlosVitorino.github.io/morning-digest/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Aardvark: OpenAI’s agentic security researcher</title>
      <link>https://openai.com/index/introducing-aardvark</link>
      <description>OpenAI introduces Aardvark, an AI-powered security researcher that autonomously finds, validates, and helps fix software vulnerabilities at scale. The system is in private beta—sign up to join early testing.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>OpenAI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>OpenAI acquires Software Applications Incorporated, maker of Sky</title>
      <link>https://openai.com/index/openai-acquires-software-applications-incorporated</link>
      <description>OpenAI has acquired Software Applications Incorporated, maker of Sky—a natural language interface for Mac that brings AI directly into your desktop experience. Together, we’re integrating Sky’s deep macOS capabilities into ChatGPT to make AI more intuitive, contextual, and action-oriented.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>OpenAI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Customizable, no-code voice agent automation with GPT-4o</title>
      <link>https://openai.com/index/retell-ai</link>
      <description>Retell AI is transforming the call center with AI voice automation powered by GPT-4o and GPT-4.1. Its no-code platform enables businesses to launch natural, real-time voice agents that cut call costs, boost CSAT, and automate customer conversations—without scripts or hold times.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>OpenAI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Surging developer productivity with custom GPTs</title>
      <link>https://openai.com/index/paf</link>
      <description>Paf adopted ChatGPT Enterprise across its entire company, with engineers using custom GPTs on a daily basis to speed up routine development tasks. Paf also integrated ChatGPT Enterprise into the grit:lab coding academy (gritlab.ax), training the next generation of software developers using an AI-augmented, systems-architecture mindset from day one. In addition to the wide range of use cases for developers and grit:lab students, 70% of Paf employees actively use ChatGPT Enterprise, spanning busin</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 08:45:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>OpenAI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Automating customer support agents</title>
      <link>https://openai.com/index/mavenagi</link>
      <description>MavenAGI is a new software company for the AI era. They recently launched an AI customer service agent, built on the flexibility of GPT-4, which a number of companies like Tripadvisor, Clickup and Rho are already using to save time and better serve their customers.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>OpenAI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Microsoft invests in and partners with OpenAI to support us building beneficial AGI</title>
      <link>https://openai.com/index/microsoft-invests-in-and-partners-with-openai</link>
      <description>Microsoft is investing $1 billion in OpenAI to support us building artificial general intelligence (AGI) with widely distributed economic benefits. We’re partnering to develop a hardware and software platform within Microsoft Azure which will scale to AGI. We’ll jointly develop new Azure AI supercomputing technologies, and Microsoft will become our exclusive cloud provider—so we’ll be working hard together to further extend Microsoft Azure’s capabilities in large-scale AI systems.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>OpenAI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Generative AI to quantify uncertainty in weather forecasting</title>
      <link>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-8474926331452026626.post-1569605132526995799</link>
      <description>Posted by Lizao (Larry) Li, Software Engineer, and Rob Carver, Research Scientist, Google Research Accurate weather forecasts can have a direct impact on people’s lives, from helping make routine decisions, like what to pack for a day’s activities, to informing urgent actions, for example, protecting people in the face of hazardous weather conditions. The importance of accurate and timely weather forecasts will only increase as the climate changes. Recognizing this, we at Google have been invest</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 18:03:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>Google AI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>AutoBNN: Probabilistic time series forecasting with compositional bayesian neural networks</title>
      <link>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-8474926331452026626.post-1799535679952845079</link>
      <description>Posted by Urs Köster, Software Engineer, Google Research Time series problems are ubiquitous, from forecasting weather and traffic patterns to understanding economic trends. Bayesian approaches start with an assumption about the data&apos;s patterns (prior probability), collecting evidence (e.g., new time series data), and continuously updating that assumption to form a posterior probability distribution. Traditional Bayesian approaches like Gaussian processes (GPs) and Structural Time Series are ext</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 20:53:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>Google AI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Computer-aided diagnosis for lung cancer screening</title>
      <link>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-8474926331452026626.post-7061041222399769838</link>
      <description>Posted by Atilla Kiraly, Software Engineer, and Rory Pilgrim, Product Manager, Google Research Lung cancer is the leading cause of cancer-related deaths globally with 1.8 million deaths reported in 2020. Late diagnosis dramatically reduces the chances of survival. Lung cancer screening via computed tomography (CT), which provides a detailed 3D image of the lungs, has been shown to reduce mortality in high-risk populations by at least 20% by detecting potential signs of cancers earlier. In the US</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 20:54:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>Google AI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Using AI to expand global access to reliable flood forecasts</title>
      <link>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-8474926331452026626.post-4615278636568583418</link>
      <description>Posted by Yossi Matias, VP Engineering &amp;amp; Research, and Grey Nearing, Research Scientist, Google Research Floods are the most common natural disaster , and are responsible for roughly $50 billion in annual financial damages worldwide. The rate of flood-related disasters has more than doubled since the year 2000 partly due to climate change . Nearly 1.5 billion people , making up 19% of the world’s population, are exposed to substantial risks from severe flood events. Upgrading early warning s</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 16:06:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>Google AI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>ScreenAI: A visual language model for UI and visually-situated language understanding</title>
      <link>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-8474926331452026626.post-520087429457973735</link>
      <description>Posted by Srinivas Sunkara and Gilles Baechler, Software Engineers, Google Research Screen user interfaces (UIs) and infographics, such as charts, diagrams and tables, play important roles in human communication and human-machine interaction as they facilitate rich and interactive user experiences. UIs and infographics share similar design principles and visual language (e.g., icons and layouts), that offer an opportunity to build a single model that can understand, reason, and interact with the</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 20:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>Google AI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>SCIN: A new resource for representative dermatology images</title>
      <link>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-8474926331452026626.post-4328167517765145678</link>
      <description>Posted by Pooja Rao, Research Scientist, Google Research Health datasets play a crucial role in research and medical education, but it can be challenging to create a dataset that represents the real world. For example, dermatology conditions are diverse in their appearance and severity and manifest differently across skin tones. Yet, existing dermatology image datasets often lack representation of everyday conditions (like rashes, allergies and infections) and skew towards lighter skin tones. Fu</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>Google AI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>MELON: Reconstructing 3D objects from images with unknown poses</title>
      <link>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-8474926331452026626.post-757976001746578714</link>
      <description>Posted by Mark Matthews, Senior Software Engineer, and Dmitry Lagun, Research Scientist, Google Research A person&apos;s prior experience and understanding of the world generally enables them to easily infer what an object looks like in whole, even if only looking at a few 2D pictures of it. Yet the capacity for a computer to reconstruct the shape of an object in 3D given only a few images has remained a difficult algorithmic problem for years. This fundamental computer vision task has applications r</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 18:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>Google AI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Cappy: Outperforming and boosting large multi-task language models with a small scorer</title>
      <link>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-8474926331452026626.post-7868032799856333119</link>
      <description>Posted by Yun Zhu and Lijuan Liu, Software Engineers, Google Research Large language model (LLM) advancements have led to a new paradigm that unifies various natural language processing (NLP) tasks within an instruction-following framework. This paradigm is exemplified by recent multi-task LLMs, such as T0 , FLAN , and OPT-IML . First, multi-task data is gathered with each task following a task-specific template, where each labeled example is converted into an instruction (e.g., &quot; Put the concep</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 19:38:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>Google AI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Talk like a graph: Encoding graphs for large language models</title>
      <link>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-8474926331452026626.post-6090481872694489715</link>
      <description>Posted by Bahare Fatemi and Bryan Perozzi, Research Scientists, Google Research Imagine all the things around you — your friends, tools in your kitchen, or even the parts of your bike. They are all connected in different ways. In computer science, the term graph is used to describe connections between objects. Graphs consist of nodes (the objects themselves) and edges (connections between two nodes, indicating a relationship between them). Graphs are everywhere now. The internet itself is a gian</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 21:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>Google AI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Chain-of-table: Evolving tables in the reasoning chain for table understanding</title>
      <link>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-8474926331452026626.post-470840348983280912</link>
      <description>Posted by Zilong Wang, Student Researcher, and Chen-Yu Lee, Research Scientist, Cloud AI Team People use tables every day to organize and interpret complex information in a structured, easily accessible format. Due to the ubiquity of such tables, reasoning over tabular data has long been a central topic in natural language processing (NLP). Researchers in this field have aimed to leverage language models to help users answer questions, verify statements, and analyze data based on tables. However</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 19:08:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>Google AI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Health-specific embedding tools for dermatology and pathology</title>
      <link>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-8474926331452026626.post-1106624361649572376</link>
      <description>Posted by Dave Steiner, Clinical Research Scientist, Google Health, and Rory Pilgrim, Product Manager, Google Research There’s a worldwide shortage of access to medical imaging expert interpretation across specialties including radiology , dermatology and pathology . Machine learning (ML) technology can help ease this burden by powering tools that enable doctors to interpret these images more accurately and efficiently. However, the development and implementation of such ML tools are often limit</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 19:33:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>Google AI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Social learning: Collaborative learning with large language models</title>
      <link>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-8474926331452026626.post-1765359719068432739</link>
      <description>Posted by Amirkeivan Mohtashami, Research Intern, and Florian Hartmann, Software Engineer, Google Research Large language models (LLMs) have significantly improved the state of the art for solving tasks specified using natural language, often reaching performance close to that of people. As these models increasingly enable assistive agents, it could be beneficial for them to learn effectively from each other, much like people do in social settings, which would allow LLM-based agents to improve e</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 18:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>Google AI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Croissant: a metadata format for ML-ready datasets</title>
      <link>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-8474926331452026626.post-8393293208018757284</link>
      <description>Posted by Omar Benjelloun, Software Engineer, Google Research, and Peter Mattson, Software Engineer, Google Core ML and President, MLCommons Association Machine learning (ML) practitioners looking to reuse existing datasets to train an ML model often spend a lot of time understanding the data, making sense of its organization, or figuring out what subset to use as features. So much time, in fact, that progress in the field of ML is hampered by a fundamental obstacle: the wide variety of data rep</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 18:26:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>Google AI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>VideoPrism: A foundational visual encoder for video understanding</title>
      <link>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-8474926331452026626.post-1695264277638670894</link>
      <description>Posted by Long Zhao, Senior Research Scientist, and Ting Liu, Senior Staff Software Engineer, Google Research An astounding number of videos are available on the Web, covering a variety of content from everyday moments people share to historical moments to scientific observations, each of which contains a unique record of the world. The right tools could help researchers analyze these videos, transforming how we understand the world around us. Videos offer dynamic visual content far more rich th</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 20:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>Google AI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Advances in private training for production on-device language models</title>
      <link>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-8474926331452026626.post-4343235509909091741</link>
      <description>Posted by Zheng Xu, Research Scientist, and Yanxiang Zhang, Software Engineer, Google Language models (LMs) trained to predict the next word given input text are the key technology for many applications [ 1 , 2 ]. In Gboard , LMs are used to improve users’ typing experience by supporting features like next word prediction (NWP), Smart Compose , smart completion and suggestion , slide to type , and proofread . Deploying models on users’ devices rather than enterprise servers has advantages like l</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 20:15:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>Google AI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Graph neural networks in TensorFlow</title>
      <link>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-8474926331452026626.post-3264694155710647310</link>
      <description>Posted by Dustin Zelle, Software Engineer, Google Research, and Arno Eigenwillig, Software Engineer, CoreML Objects and their relationships are ubiquitous in the world around us, and relationships can be as important to understanding an object as its own attributes viewed in isolation — take for example transportation networks, production networks, knowledge graphs, or social networks. Discrete mathematics and computer science have a long history of formalizing such networks as graphs , consisti</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 19:17:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>Google AI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>A decoder-only foundation model for time-series forecasting</title>
      <link>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-8474926331452026626.post-6956767920612914706</link>
      <description>Posted by Rajat Sen and Yichen Zhou, Google Research Time-series forecasting is ubiquitous in various domains, such as retail, finance, manufacturing, healthcare and natural sciences. In retail use cases, for example, it has been observed that improving demand forecasting accuracy can meaningfully reduce inventory costs and increase revenue. Deep learning (DL) models have emerged as a popular approach for forecasting rich, multivariate, time-series data because they have proven to perform well i</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 19:07:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>Google AI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>MobileDiffusion: Rapid text-to-image generation on-device</title>
      <link>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-8474926331452026626.post-5966553114967673984</link>
      <description>Posted by Yang Zhao, Senior Software Engineer, and Tingbo Hou, Senior Staff Software Engineer, Core ML Text-to-image diffusion models have shown exceptional capabilities in generating high-quality images from text prompts. However, leading models feature billions of parameters and are consequently expensive to run, requiring powerful desktops or servers (e.g., Stable Diffusion , DALL·E , and Imagen ). While recent advancements in inference solutions on Android via MediaPipe and iOS via Core ML h</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 21:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>Google AI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Mixed-input matrix multiplication performance optimizations</title>
      <link>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-8474926331452026626.post-5144906729109253495</link>
      <description>Posted by Manish Gupta, Staff Software Engineer, Google Research AI-driven technologies are weaving themselves into the fabric of our daily routines, with the potential to enhance our access to knowledge and boost our overall productivity. The backbone of these applications lies in large language models (LLMs). LLMs are memory-intensive and typically require specialized hardware accelerators to efficiently deliver tens of exaflops of computing power. This blog post shows how we can start address</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 19:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>Google AI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Exphormer: Scaling transformers for graph-structured data</title>
      <link>tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-8474926331452026626.post-1418736582601940076</link>
      <description>Posted by Ameya Velingker, Research Scientist, Google Research, and Balaji Venkatachalam, Software Engineer, Google Graphs , in which objects and their relations are represented as nodes (or vertices) and edges (or links) between pairs of nodes, are ubiquitous in computing and machine learning (ML). For example, social networks, road networks, and molecular structure and interactions are all domains in which underlying datasets have a natural graph structure. ML can be used to learn the properti</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 22:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>Google AI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>The Download: unraveling a death threat mystery, and AI voice recreation for musicians</title>
      <link>https://www.technologyreview.com/2026/02/16/1133008/the-download-unraveling-a-death-threat-mystery-and-ai-voice-recreation-for-musicians/</link>
      <description>This is today&amp;#8217;s edition of The Download, our weekday newsletter that provides a daily dose of what&amp;#8217;s going on in the world of technology. Hackers made death threats against this security researcher. Big mistake. In April 2024, a mysterious someone using the online handles “Waifu” and “Judische” began posting death threats on Telegram and Discord channels aimed&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 13:10:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>MIT Technology Review</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>The scientist using AI to hunt for antibiotics just about everywhere</title>
      <link>https://www.technologyreview.com/2026/02/16/1132516/cesar-de-la-fuente-using-ai-antibiotics-hunt/</link>
      <description>When he was just a teenager trying to decide what to do with his life, César de la Fuente compiled a list of the world’s biggest problems. He ranked them inversely by how much money governments were spending to solve them. Antimicrobial resistance topped the list.&amp;#160; Twenty years on, the problem has not gone away.&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>MIT Technology Review</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Powering tax donations with AI powered personalized recommendations</title>
      <link>https://openai.com/index/trustbank</link>
      <description>TRUSTBANK partnered with Recursive to build Choice AI using OpenAI models, delivering personalized, conversational recommendations that simplify Furusato Nozei gift discovery. A multi-agent system helps donors navigate thousands of options and find gifts that match their preferences.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>OpenAI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Cisco and OpenAI redefine enterprise engineering with AI agents</title>
      <link>https://openai.com/index/cisco</link>
      <description>Cisco and OpenAI redefine enterprise engineering with Codex, an AI software agent embedded in workflows to speed builds, automate defect fixes, and enable AI-native development.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>OpenAI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Zenken boosts a lean sales team with ChatGPT Enterprise</title>
      <link>https://openai.com/index/zenken</link>
      <description>By rolling out ChatGPT Enterprise company-wide, Zenken has boosted sales performance, cut preparation time, and increased proposal success rates. AI-supported workflows are helping a lean team deliver more personalized, effective customer engagement.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 16:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>OpenAI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Announcing OpenAI Grove Cohort 2</title>
      <link>https://openai.com/index/openai-grove</link>
      <description>Applications are now open for OpenAI Grove Cohort 2, a 5-week founder program designed for individuals at any stage, from pre-idea to product. Participants receive $50K in API credits, early access to AI tools, and hands-on mentorship from the OpenAI team.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>OpenAI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>One in a million: celebrating the customers shaping AI’s future</title>
      <link>https://openai.com/index/one-in-a-million-customers</link>
      <description>More than one million customers around the world now use OpenAI to empower their teams and unlock new opportunities. This post highlights how companies like PayPal, Virgin Atlantic, BBVA, Cisco, Moderna, and Canva are transforming the way work gets done with AI.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>OpenAI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Continuously hardening ChatGPT Atlas against prompt injection</title>
      <link>https://openai.com/index/hardening-atlas-against-prompt-injection</link>
      <description>OpenAI is strengthening ChatGPT Atlas against prompt injection attacks using automated red teaming trained with reinforcement learning. This proactive discover-and-patch loop helps identify novel exploits early and harden the browser agent’s defenses as AI becomes more agentic.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>OpenAI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Evaluating chain-of-thought monitorability</title>
      <link>https://openai.com/index/evaluating-chain-of-thought-monitorability</link>
      <description>OpenAI introduces a new framework and evaluation suite for chain-of-thought monitorability, covering 13 evaluations across 24 environments. Our findings show that monitoring a model’s internal reasoning is far more effective than monitoring outputs alone, offering a promising path toward scalable control as AI systems grow more capable.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>OpenAI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>AI literacy resources for teens and parents</title>
      <link>https://openai.com/index/ai-literacy-resources-for-teens-and-parents</link>
      <description>OpenAI shares new AI literacy resources to help teens and parents use ChatGPT thoughtfully, safely, and with confidence. The guides include expert-vetted tips for responsible use, critical thinking, healthy boundaries, and supporting teens through emotional or sensitive topics.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>OpenAI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Deepening our collaboration with the U.S. Department of Energy</title>
      <link>https://openai.com/index/us-department-of-energy-collaboration</link>
      <description>OpenAI and the U.S. Department of Energy have signed a memorandum of understanding to deepen collaboration on AI and advanced computing in support of scientific discovery. The agreement builds on ongoing work with national laboratories and helps establish a framework for applying AI to high-impact research across the DOE ecosystem.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>OpenAI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Introducing OpenAI Academy for News Organizations</title>
      <link>https://openai.com/index/openai-academy-for-news-organizations</link>
      <description>OpenAI is launching the OpenAI Academy for News Organizations, a new learning hub built with the American Journalism Project and The Lenfest Institute to help newsrooms use AI effectively. The Academy offers training, practical use cases, and responsible-use guidance to support journalists, editors, and publishers as they adopt AI in their reporting and operations.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>OpenAI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Measuring AI’s capability to accelerate biological research</title>
      <link>https://openai.com/index/accelerating-biological-research-in-the-wet-lab</link>
      <description>OpenAI introduces a real-world evaluation framework to measure how AI can accelerate biological research in the wet lab. Using GPT-5 to optimize a molecular cloning protocol, the work explores both the promise and risks of AI-assisted experimentation.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>OpenAI Blog</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>BBVA and OpenAI collaborate to transform global banking</title>
      <link>https://openai.com/index/bbva-collaboration-expansion</link>
      <description>BBVA is expanding its work with OpenAI through a multi-year AI transformation program, rolling out ChatGPT Enterprise to all 120,000 employees. Together, the companies will develop AI solutions that enhance customer interactions, streamline operations, and help build an AI-native banking experience.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <category>ai</category>
      <source>OpenAI Blog</source>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>